I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame
We were all swept away
I'll come and get you; I am always ready to fight
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
There will always be something you cannot control
So don't take all of the blame
We will overcome. Your salvation has begun
We were all swept away
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
No signs, no lights
There will always be something you cannot control
Such a mess all over
We will overcome
Don't kill your hopes
Your salvation has begun
You make me realize who I need
No signs, no lights
Such a mess all over
I'll be there, hold on
Don't kill your hopes
They'll change you somehow
You make me realize who I need
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn
I'll be there, hold on
The shadows appear
They'll change you somehow
Illusions are born
So where are you now?
The fallen angels you run with don't know
I'll reach you by dawn
The shadows appear
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Illusions are born
Torn old sepia photographs show
The fallen angels you run with don't know
Our fragile preious world
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Must discard it, respond to the call
Torn old sepia photographs show
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:鱼子酱&paper   翻译:小悠&冰蝶   校对:夜神&Lucifer   时间轴:阿水   压制:久嘉
Our fragile precious world
Must discard it, respond to the call
Childhood
Reunion
You...
お前…
Yuu?
優ちゃん…
何してる
What the hell are you doing?!
Activate the curse and kill him immediately!
早く呪詛入れて殺せ　優
What?
Do it now!
早くしろ
でも…
But...
Tsk. You little shit!
クソが
ふざけんな　てめぇなんで殺さなかった
What the fuck?!
Why didn't you kill him?!
Huh? But he's...
え…あ　いや…
H-Hey, are you okay?
大丈夫か
くだらねえ心配すんな
I don't need you sniveling over me!
Eyes on the enemy, you fuckin' brat!
前だけ見てろ　ガキ
This is a goddamn battlefield!
ここは戦場だぞ
What the hell, Yuu?!
馬鹿優　何やってる
You could've killed him just now!
今のは殺せただろうが
Why didn't you activate the curse?
なんで鬼呪を発動しなかった
Yuu, what's wrong?
優くん…どうしたの
Yuu...
優さん…
Mika...
ミカが…
俺の家族が…
My family is...
吸血鬼の中にいる
with the vampires.
Mika! It's you, right?
お前　ミカなのか
Mika...
ミカ…ミカ…
I-It's really you!
ほ…ほんとにミカなんだ…
Y-Yuu...
ゆ…優ちゃん…
My, what an adorable reaction.
何あの可愛い態度
It's your dear, long-lost Hyakuya Yuuichirou.
懐かしいの百夜優一郎くん
The one you've been dreaming about all this time.
君が拘ってたわけだなあ
What a wonderfully destined reunion.
でも　まさかの運命の再会
I'm almost in tears.
涙が出ちゃいそう
So, what would you like to do?
で…どうするんです
Those humans have most likely been manipulating him.
たぶん優ちゃん　人間どもに利用されてますよ
I'll save him.
当然救う
From the filthy hands of those wretched humans?
醜い人間どもの手から？
Yes.
ああ
But he's a human himself.
でも彼も人間ですよ
人間は決して僕らの仲間にならない
We vampires were never meant to coexist alongside them.
あ　そうだ
Ah, how does this sound?
I'll take a page out of Krul's book.
じゃあクルルが君にしたように
僕が優ちゃんを吸血鬼にしてあげ…
If I turn him into a vamp—
If you lay even a finger on him, I'll kill you.
優ちゃんに手を出したら殺すぞ　お前
I'm kidding, of course.
冗談ですよ
It's not like you to get so worked up.
珍しく熱くなっちゃって
Shall I lend a hand instead, then?
ま　じゃあ手を貸してあげましょうか
I'll take care of the other humans,
他の人間は僕が止めてあげるから
so you can save your beloved princess.
君は大切なお姫様を奪ってきなさいよ
I see you've made friends, Yuu.
優ちゃん…仲間がいるんだ…
You're too kind.
優しいもんね
But they're taking advantage of your kindness.
でもだからこそ　優しすぎるからこそ　騙される
人間どもは　仲間ヅラしているそいつらは
The greed of the humans, your so-called "friends," knows no bounds, Yuu.
とても欲深いんだ　優ちゃん
Shall we get to work?
さて　やりますか
優ちゃん以外の人間を　皆殺しにしましょう
It's time to kill all the humans! Except for Yuu, of course.
私をお呼びと聞きましたが
I hear my presence is required,
Seventh Progenitor.
第七位始祖様
Oh, Crowley.
ああ　クローリー君かあ
I've been waiting for you.
待ってたよ
He's...
あいつ…
I made a little detour on the way.
ちょっと寄り道しててね
Did you come across something of interest?
何か面白いものでもあったかい
Well, I suppose we might as well
call it a day, now that you're here.
でも　君たちがいたら　もうゲームセットだねぇ
よし　家畜にしよう
Oh, how about we take them as livestock?
殺さず生け捕る
Capture the vampire extermination unit alive.
吸血鬼殲滅部隊　家畜化計画
Operation Domestication.
Sounds good to me.
悪くないね
Shit, more nobles.
くそ　また貴族が増えやがった
We're done here.
終わりだ
All units, prepare to retreat!
総員　離脱態勢
Huh?!
W-Wait a minute!
ち…ちょっと待ってくれよ
My last family member, Mika, is over there!
向こうにミカが
俺の家族がいるんだ
So... So we can't retreat!
だから…だから撤退は…
じゃあここで皆殺しにされりゃいいってのか
So you're trying to get everyone here killed, is that it?
Yuu.
優くん
Yuu, he's right.
優さん　今は
We have no choice.
Retreat!
撤退だ
Keep your formation and retreat to the second defense line!
陣形を保ったまま　第二防衛ラインへ後退
Uh-uh, no escaping allowed.
逃がさないよーん
Break up!
散開しろ
You!
お前
Are you insane, Yuu?!
何やってる　優
You!
お前　お前
It was you!
Yuu!
優さん
For fuck's sake...
くそガキが
Lieutenant Colonel?!
中佐
You're fast, but you lack experience.
速ーい
けどまだ若ーい
And even a lion can be brought low by his injuries.
そして　ライオンも
手負いじゃ剣線が鈍いね
Lieutenant Colonel Guren!
グレン様
Move.
邪魔
End of the line, sweetie.
はい　待った
Oh, nice. Not so stoic after all, huh?
いいね　そういう顔もするんだ
Mito!
美十さん
ええ　大丈夫
I'm fine.
Looks like they plan on holding us off at all costs.
どうあっても　行かせてはくれないようですね
We'll have to kill them.
始末するしかないでしょう
Easier said than done.
簡単に言うねぇ
If we could do that,
we'd be on our way back home by now.
それができたら　ここまで苦労してないよ
諦めろ　お前らは家畜になるしかない
Give it up.
You have no destiny but that of livestock.
You heard the man.
そういうこと
Focus!
集中しろ
What are you doing?!
何やってんだ　すぐ立て
Stand up!
S-Sorry.
ご…ごめん
Well, well, we meet again.
いやあ　また会ったね
This time, I won't let you go.
今度は見逃してあげないよ
Guren!
グレン
Behind you!
後ろ
First, I'll have a taste of your—
まずは君から味見…
Why the scary face?
そんなに怒るなよ
I'm just fooling around with you.
可愛い冗談じゃないか
Mika.
ミカ
Yuu, leave everything behind and escape with me.
優ちゃん　全部捨てて僕と逃げよう
Huh? What do you mean, escape?
逃げるって何だよ
Actually, why are you even with that vampire?!
つーか　お前なんであの吸血鬼と一緒に
It doesn't matter!
いいから
Yuu!
優さん
よそ見はダメだよ
Eyes on the prize, dear.
Hey! Hold on!
ちょっと待て　ふざけんな　ミカ
Quit messing around, Mika! Give me an explanation!
何がどうなってんのか説明しろ
You shouldn't stay there for any longer, Yuu.
優ちゃんはあそこにいちゃだめなんだ
You'll be deceived by the humans.
人間に利用される　だから
Come with—
Just stop, goddamnit!
いいから　ちょっと止まれ
That's enough!
いい加減にしろ
They'll deceive me?
人間に利用される　何だよそれ
What are you getting at?
Aren't you also...
お前は
お…お前もう人間じゃないのか
Y-You're not human anymore?
俺のせいか
I-Is it my fault?
俺が逃げたせいで
Is it because I ran away?
違う　優ちゃんは悪くない
No! You did nothing wrong!
だって
But...
いいから行こう　ここは危険なんだ
Let's just go.
It's not safe here.
優ちゃん　お願い
Yuu, please.
俺はだめだよ　ミカ
I can't, Mika.
俺は行けない
I can't go.
仲間が…
My friends are—
They're not your friends! Don't let them deceive you!
違う　あれは仲間じゃない
騙されないで　優ちゃん
They're just using you!
人間どもは　君を利用して
シノアさん
Shinoa!
シノア
お願いだ　優ちゃん　振り返らないで
Please, Yuu!
Don't look back!
後ろには何もない
There's nothing for you here.
何もないんだ
Nothing!
手を放せ
Unhand her!
優ちゃん
Yuu!
放せよ
Let go!
行っちゃだめだ　優ちゃん
You mustn't, Yuu!
放せ
Let go of me!
行っちゃだめだ　あいつらは君を利用しようとしているだけだ
You can't go!
They're just trying to use you!
いやあー
No!
やめろぉ
Stop it!
僕と行こう　優ちゃん
Come with me, Yuu!
うるせぇ
Shut up!
Y-Yuu, run away...
優さん…逃げ…
家畜が喋るなよ
Livestock don't talk.
Please, stop...
やめろ　やめてくれ
もう無理だよ　優ちゃん　諦めるんだ
It's too late, Yuu.
You need to give up.
ゆ…優ちゃん
Y-Yuu...?
おい　阿朱羅丸
Hey, Asuramaru.
んー？何
Hm? What?
これなんだ
What's going on here?
お前　俺を乗っ取ろうとしてるのか
Are you trying to possess me?
違うよ　僕は何もしてない
I've done nothing of the sort.
でも困ったなあ　これ
But this is a problem.
Huh?
まさかこの僕が　取り憑いた人間の化物っぷりに怯えることになるとはね
I never thought I'd be intimidated by the monster inside you.
あの空を見てよ
Look at that sky.
呪われた世界を照らすように天井が開き始めた
The heavens are opening,
as if to shine on this cursed world.
ねぇ　優　ミカの言う通りだ
Mika's right, Yuu.
まだ間に合うなら　二人で人間から逃げた方がいい
It'd be best if you escaped from the humans with him.
じゃないともう
Otherwise,
人じゃいられなく
your own humanity will be—
どうした
What's wrong?
手遅れみたい
I guess it's too late.
君の人間じゃない部分の暴走が始まる
The monster within you is about to be unleashed.
始まった
It's started.
やっぱり　人間どもは優ちゃんを
So they really were experimenting on him.
だめだ　優ちゃん　僕と一緒に…
No, Yuu!
Come with me!
ちょっとまずそうなのが出て…
Well, looks like we have quite the predicament...
凄いわ　こりゃぁ
Now that's something you don't see every day.
優ちゃん
Yuu!
Aw, now my clothes are all dirty.
服が汚れちゃったよ
なんだよ　あれ
What is that?
人間は気味の悪い化物を作るなぁ
The humans came up with such a scary monster.
どうする　フェリド君
Well, Ferid?
Hm?
あれ　何
What have you created?
さて　なんだろうな
I wonder what, indeed.
大方君ら人間お得意の人体実験でしょう
Looks like your species' specialty to me—
human experimentation.
その際限ない欲望はどっから沸くのかなあ
Your limitless greed never fails to astound me.
正直怖くなるよ
Honestly, it's rather scary.
おまけに君らはいつもそれを制御できないし　ほら
Not to mention, it always breaks free
of your control one way or another.
See?
つ…罪人　罪人は　みな…皆殺しだ
S-S-S-Sinners...
All sinners must be s-s-slaughtered...
シノア　お前がなんとかしろ
Shinoa!
You have to do something!
今の優なら戻って来れる
There's still a chance we can bring him back!
What?
だめだ　優ちゃん
Stop, Yuu!
人間を殺しちゃ…
You mustn't kill humans!
あ…あなた　何で
Wh-Why did you...
黙れ　人間　優ちゃんを利用しやがって
Shut your treacherous mouth, human.
How dare you treat Yuu like some plaything?
くそ　傷が修復しない
Damn, my injury won't heal.
皆…殺しだ
Slaugh... ter...
シノア
Shinoa!
早くしろ　全員死ぬぞ
Hurry the hell up or we'll all die!
シノア
Shinoa!
ゆ　優さん　お願いします
Y-Yuu, please! Snap out of it!
正気に戻ってください
Don't touch Yuu with your filthy hands!
汚い手で優ちゃんに触るな
Yuu!
優さん
お願いです　優さん
Please, Yuu!
優さん
Yuu!
優さん　優さん
優さん
Yuu...
人間どもが　人間どもが
Damn those humans...
Damn them all to Hell!
派手な演出だろう　あれが俺の切り札だよ
Quite a show, isn't it?
That's my trump card.
でも結果は何も出なかったじゃない
What a shame it did absolutely nothing.
いや出たね　俺たちはなんせただの時間稼ぎだからな
Oh, but it made all the difference.
After all, we were just stalling for time.
おっと　バレた
Oops, caught red-handed.
でももう遅いよ
But it's too late.
敵を貫け　百虎丸
Pierce the enemies, Byakkomaru.
Oh, and try not to hit Guren.
グレンには当てないようにね　ズドン
Boom.
くそ
Shit!
Whew, that was close.
危ない　危ない
If it weren't for his big mouth, I might have died.
彼の忠告が無かったら　死んでたかもね
これは　これは
Oh, deary me.
分家のクズの割りには良くやった　一瀬中佐
Not bad for an Ichinose scumbag, Lieutenant Colonel.
あとは柊家が引きず
The Hiiragi family will take it from here.
行くぞ　貴族どもを生け捕りにする
Move out!
Take the nobles alive!
人間に　日本帝鬼軍に
We'll show them that we humans,
the Japanese Imperial Demon Army,
我ら柊家に逆らう者がどうなるか
and those of us in the Hiiragi family
骨の髄まで思い知らせる必要がある
have no mercy for those who oppose us.
やれ
Attack.
馴染めた白　鳥がご隅　鼓動獲たツボミも
najimeta shiro torikago sumi
I used to like the light, my corner of the cage
kodou eta tsubomi mo
I'm a flower bud made flesh
置き去り声　眩めた　記憶の影
okizarigoe kurameta kioku no kage
Blinding memories cry after me
I need your blood
i need your blood
You really love 唱える
you read love tonaeru
You speak of love to me
足掻くRed Light
agaku red light
The red lights dance
嗅ぎ分けた音　音と
kagiwaketa neon to
The neon lamps
こじ開けたReasonが
kojiaketa reason ga
and the madness of the world
ただ平行に並ぶ
tada heikou ni narabu
share a vanishing point
Come on break it down for me!
Come on, break it down for me
come on, break it down for me
A river will flow
a river will flow
KEYがない「欲しい」でも　利害鳴る鈴
My desires remain unfulfilled
key ga nai hoshii demo
rigai naru suzu
A melody of ups and downs
懺悔さえ乾いた　４拍子が　奏でた意図を辿る
rigai naru suzu
zange sae kawaita yonbyoushi ga
Our song follows the sheet of our will,
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
no longer capable of penance
木漏れ日の　赤が　騒ぐ
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
Crimson beams assault my vision
komorebi no aka ga sawagu
次回　終わりのセラフ
Next time, on Seraph of the End:
We're All
Sinners
"We're All Sinners."